

- + 234 Valleymede Drive Toronto ON
- + kathy.toufighi@gmail.com 416-473-9112

CAREER OBJECTIVE (at this juncture)

The big advantage of being a frontend developer is a continuous need for improving the UI experience through collecting data, collaboration, implementation and development. I have been playing a key role in improving that experience. I want to continue working in the intersection of design and technology so I can build web applications and tools that contribute and improve human experience in this digital landscape.

TECHNOLOGIES

LANGUAGES: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, Ruby, PHP, SQL, WordPress, HAML markup, Bootstrap

VERSION CONTROL: Git, Github, **PACKAGE MANAGERS:** Gulp, NPM

SOFTWARE / TOOLS: Adobe CS, Sketch, InVision, , Salesforce / Pardot, JIRA, Google Analytics, Linux command line and OS management using SSH ON MY TO LEARN LIST: ES6, React, Angular

EXPERIENCE

Front-end developer at Financeit (fintech industry)

TORONTO | MAY 1, 2017 - PRESENT

- Part of my work was to write, debug, deploy code. I created responsive landing-pages for our marketing campaigns. The result had a large impact on improving our sign up experience and increased acquisition. It also had 41% increase in lead generation since it was implemented. The overall experience received positive feedback from our partners and consumers.
- Pitched a new email strategy to better the delivery of our core messaging. These new email templates resulted in bringing a big boost in click through rate and average time spent on each communication piece.
- I contributed in writing clean and reusable code, housekeeping tasks such as performing quality assurance, code review on Github.

Designer, consultant and project manager

TORONTO | SEPT 2010 - MAY 2017

• Creating new relationship to increase revenue for eight organizations through creative strategy and engaging design in finance, legal, arts and culture, logistics, health care, not-for-profit, food, and publishing industries.

List of clients: www.tirgan.ca, http://phyzig.herokuapp.com, http://gofreightfox.com, Transcontinental, The Scotiabank, Evans Investment Counsel and Tirgan Festival.

Art Director & Production Manager at Style Communications Inc.

TORONTO | OCT 2005 - AUG 2010

- Lead our creative department by overseeing the creative process, planning our photoshoot, scouting for talent, working closely with our editorial team and finally creating engaging layouts for our readers and partners.
- An influx of 20% increase in advertising sales occurred after joining the company as an art director. We took a new approach and redesigned the face and brand of the outdated Canadian Jeweller magazine.

Designer at Up Inc.

TORONTO SEPT 2004 - SEPT 2005

 As a designer I successfully translated design briefs and client's vision into concrete solutions pertaining to special projects, product launches and marketing collateral within finance and hospitality industries. List of clients: RBC, Herman Miller and Fairmont Hotel chain, HBC among others.

EDUCATION (more in works)

Full-Stack Web Development | http://bitmaker.co Certificate in Search Engine Optimization | http://www.marketmotive.com Bachelor Degree in Design | York University/Sheridan College

TORONTO | OCT 2016 - JAN 2017 APR 2015 - JUL 2015 TORONTO | SEPT 1997 - APR 2001